https://www.linkedin.com/in/leonard-volovets

lvolovets@yahoo.com

Experienced Solutions Architect with proven skills in designing and implementing innovative technical solutions for a large global company. Wide range of experience across various technologies and architectures. Especially effective working with an international audience, building consensus and reaching results. Self-starter with a passion for solving business problems. Strategic thinker with an effective communication style and ability to break down complex technical ideas for non-technical audience. AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate, currently working on additional AWS certifications.

Technical Skills

- HTML, JavaScript, CSS, jQuery, Node.js
- XML, JSON, RESTful API
- Amazon Web Services
- Agile development
- Business Analysis
- Technical Architecture
- Sharepoint

- Responsive Web Design
- SQL, SQL Server Management Studio
- LotusScript, Visual Basic
- .NET and Java concepts
- Domino development and administration
- Informatica/ETL/LEI
- NoSQL concepts

Experience

Cargill Incorporated, Minneapolis, MN

1995 - Aug. 2017

Solutions Architect, IBM Notes/Domino Technical Service Owner (2013 – Aug. 2017)

- Engaged and collaborated with Cargill users all over the world to discover creative solutions
- Championed the use of Notes/Domino technology throughout the company
- Supervised external contractors working on Cargill projects
- Collaborated with SMEs and Product Owners in different BUs to enhance and improve existing applications
- Determined the vision and direction for the service which includes a 2500+ application portfolio
 - Contributed a key idea for reducing the effort of converting Cargill's Domino application portfolio to SAML-based authentication by 90%
 - Successfully overcame technical hurdles of Domino 64Gb file size limit by leading company-wide implementation of DAOS (Domino Attachment Object Store) service

Technical Team Lead (2009 – 2012)

- Served as "hands-on" Technical Team Lead for a group of onshore and offshore developers
- Coached individual developers on technical and business aspects of their job
- Offered constructive feedback to facilitate technical and personal development
- Architected technical solutions based on requirements coming out of "deep dives"

Sr. Technical Analyst (1996 – 2008)

- Developed web and client applications using Lotus Notes/Domino technology
- Worked with worldwide Accounting, Trading, Sales, CRM, Plant Ops and Admin functions
- Developed two major systems (PSM and Balance Sheet) with thousands of WW users
 - Served as the lead technical resource during the development of a web-based PSM (Process Safety Management) suite of applications. Performed business analysis, design, development and implementation of system components to 400+ plant locations, across 35 Business Units, used by 15K users across the world. The system has been in existence since 2005 and is a key component in improving Cargill's process safety metrics. Achieved at **least a \$10 million in ANNUAL savings** for the corporation.
 - Helped establish common, repeatable, and efficient processes by implementing a web-based electronic Balance Sheet Reconciliation system. Used by Cargill's 25 Business Units and functions across North America, Europe, Africa and Asia Pacific.

Technical Analyst (1995 – 1996)

North Star Steel (Division of Cargill)

- Supported Payroll, Finance and Admin applications at eight US NSS locations
- Traveled to various locations to install and upgrade system components and perform S/36 to RS6000 conversions
- Developed enhancements to existing systems based on new business and user requirements

Johnson Brothers Liquor Company - St. Paul, MN

1989 – 1995

Programmer/Analyst (1989 – 1995)

- System support of S/36 applications used by headquarters and 20+ remote US locations
- System enhancements to existing Sales, Order Entry, Inventory, Accounting and Day End modules
- Supervised a small group of employees involved in Day End order processing

Education

- Master of Science, Applied Mathematics University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN
 - Taught undergraduate Algebra, Pre-calculus, Calculus and Finite Math
 - Graded homework assignments and administered tests/quizzes
 - Held office hours for individual help and tutoring
- Bachelor of Arts, Mathematics, Magna Cum Laude Macalester College, St. Paul, MN

Certifications

AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate

• IBM CLP Principal Application Developer

Awards

- 2005 Cargill IT Award for Innovation (Traceability portal)
 - Built an application which integrated with several backend systems supplying product traceability data (animal feed and grain tracking)
- 2004 Cargill Chairman's Innovation Award (Cargill AgHorizons Marketing Services)
 - Built a Lotus Notes-based client application to help customer representatives take their data "on the go"
- 2000 Cargill Chairman's Innovation Award (Cargill AgHorizons.com portal)
 - Instrumental in design, development and support of Cargill Ag Horizons, a customer portal. The site was prominently featured for a week by Lotus on its homepage during 2000.

Professional Interests

- Cybersecurity
- Serverless computing/AWS Lambda
- Big Data
- Machine Learning/Al

Foreign Languages

• Fluent in Russian and Ukrainian, some Spanish and French